China/LOCATION ratcheted/O up/O its/O opposition/O to/O the/O U.S./LOCATION investigation/O into/O its/O intellectual/O property/O practices/O ,/O accusing/O the/O Trump/PERSON administration/O of/O sabotaging/O the/O international/O trading/O system/O ,/O and/O again/O pledging/O to/O defend/O its/O interests/O if/O necessary/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O ,/O Ministry/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Commerce/ORGANIZATION spokesman/O Gao/PERSON Feng/PERSON said/O at/O a/O briefing/O Thursday/DATE in/O Beijing/LOCATION that/O the/O two/O nations/O have/O more/O shared/O interests/O than/O disputes/O and/O stressed/O that/O cooperation/O is/O the/O best/O way/O to/O address/O any/O differences/O ./O 
``/O The/O U.S./LOCATION investigation/O of/O China/LOCATION based/O on/O domestic/O laws/O sabotages/O the/O existing/O international/O trading/O system/O ,/O and/O has/O poured/O cold/O water/O on/O all/O parties/O that/O have/O been/O working/O to/O promote/O bilateral/O economic/O ties/O ,/O ''/O Gao/PERSON said/O ./O 
He/O added/O that/O China/LOCATION was/O strongly/O displeased/O by/O what/O it/O called/O ``/O unilateral/O and/O protectionist/O ''/O action/O ./O 
The/O remarks/O took/O a/O sharper/O tone/O than/O the/O ministry/O 's/O statement/O following/O an/O announcement/O Friday/DATE of/O the/O investigation/O by/O U.S./LOCATION Trade/O Representative/O Robert/PERSON Lighthizer/PERSON ./O 
The/O U.S./LOCATION is/O probing/O China/LOCATION 's/O practices/O on/O intellectual/O property/O ,/O technology/O transfer/O and/O innovation/O to/O determine/O if/O the/O behavior/O is/O ``/O unreasonable/O or/O discriminatory/O ,/O ''/O or/O restricts/O U.S./LOCATION commerce/O ./O 
President/O Donald/PERSON Trump/PERSON asked/O Lighthizer/PERSON earlier/O this/O month/O to/O consider/O such/O a/O move/O ./O 
Gao/PERSON said/O China/LOCATION hopes/O to/O work/O with/O the/O U.S./LOCATION to/O consolidate/O achievements/O from/O previous/O negotiations/O and/O to/O reach/O further/O positive/O outcomes/O ./O 
Trade/O tensions/O between/O the/O world/O 's/O two/O biggest/O economies/O have/O showed/O signs/O of/O heating/O up/O after/O a/O short/O honeymoon/O period/O ./O 
Earlier/O this/O week/O ,/O the/O U.S./LOCATION asked/O the/O World/ORGANIZATION Trade/ORGANIZATION Organization/ORGANIZATION to/O set/O up/O a/O dispute/O settlement/O panel/O to/O examine/O China/LOCATION 's/O administration/O of/O tariff/O rate/O quotas/O on/O agricultural/O products/O including/O wheat/O ,/O rice/O and/O corn/O ,/O which/O could/O force/O the/O Asian/MISC nation/O to/O change/O its/O policies/O or/O face/O retaliation/O in/O the/O scenario/O of/O a/O U.S./LOCATION victory/O ./O 
Read/O More/O :/O China/O Focuses/O on/O Avoiding/MISC Trade/MISC War/MISC as/O Xi-Trump/O Honeymoon/O Ends/O China/LOCATION expressed/O regret/O at/O the/O U.S./LOCATION decision/O to/O move/O forward/O with/O the/O case/O ,/O and/O will/O properly/O address/O the/O issue/O under/O the/O WTO/ORGANIZATION rules/O ,/O said/O Gao/PERSON ./O 
The/O U.S./LOCATION asked/O China/LOCATION for/O consultations/O in/O December/DATE ,/O and/O China/LOCATION has/O provided/O clarification/O and/O offered/O resolution/O ,/O the/O spokesman/O said/O ./O 
He/O added/O that/O the/O recent/O anti-dumping/O reviews/O China/LOCATION launched/O on/O two/O types/O of/O optical/O fiber/O products/O made/O in/O the/O U.S./LOCATION were/O not/O retaliatory/O action/O against/O the/O U.S./LOCATION probe/O ./O 
``/O The/O two/O cases/O are/O conducted/O completely/O in/O accordance/O with/O the/O law/O ,/O ''/O Gao/PERSON said/O ./O 
The/O ministry/O announced/O Tuesday/DATE that/O it/O will/O review/O anti-dumping/O measures/O against/O dispersion/O unshifted/O single-mode/O optical/O fiber/O made/O in/O the/O U.S./LOCATION and/O European/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O potential/O step/O toward/O higher/O tariffs/O on/O those/O imports/O ./O 
It/O marked/O the/O second/O investigation/O in/O a/O week/O after/O another/O probe/O on/O Aug./DATE 18/DATE to/O decide/O whether/O to/O extend/O anti-dumping/O duties/O on/O U.S./LOCATION and/O Japanese/MISC optical/O fiber/O preform/O ,/O a/O glass/O product/O used/O in/O fiber-optic/O cables/O ./O 
