Amazon.com/ORGANIZATION Inc./ORGANIZATION will/O begin/O selling/O Nike/ORGANIZATION shoes/O directly/O through/O a/O brand-registry/O program/O designed/O to/O keep/O counterfeit/O goods/O off/O the/O site/O ,/O according/O to/O a/O person/O familiar/O with/O the/O situation/O ./O 
The/O approach/O lets/O Nike/ORGANIZATION Inc./ORGANIZATION take/O greater/O control/O over/O how/O its/O products/O are/O sold/O ,/O helping/O ensure/O that/O knockoff/O shoes/O are/O n't/O offered/O by/O third/O parties/O on/O the/O e-commerce/O marketplace/O ,/O said/O the/O person/O ,/O who/O asked/O not/O to/O be/O named/O because/O the/O arrangement/O is/O n't/O yet/O public/O ./O 
Shoes/O are/O popular/O products/O for/O counterfeiters/O ,/O and/O Nike/ORGANIZATION 's/O global/O brand/O is/O an/O especially/O alluring/O target/O ./O 
That/O 's/O put/O pressure/O on/O the/O athletic-apparel/O giant/O to/O police/O online/O sales/O more/O aggressively/O ./O 
Lindsay/PERSON Drucker/PERSON Mann/PERSON ,/O an/O analyst/O at/O Goldman/ORGANIZATION Sachs/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION Inc./ORGANIZATION ,/O said/O earlier/O that/O Nike/ORGANIZATION may/O be/O close/O to/O forging/O a/O closer/O relationship/O with/O Amazon/LOCATION ./O 
Currently/O ,/O Nike/ORGANIZATION is/O available/O on/O Amazon/ORGANIZATION 's/O Zappos/O site/O ,/O but/O not/O directly/O through/O the/O parent/O company/O ./O 
It/O 's/O unclear/O how/O much/O more/O Nike/ORGANIZATION merchandise/O might/O ultimately/O flow/O through/O Amazon/LOCATION ,/O but/O the/O prospect/O of/O a/O special/O relationship/O between/O the/O two/O companies/O sent/O shoe-retailer/O stocks/O tumbling/O ./O 
Foot/ORGANIZATION Locker/ORGANIZATION Inc./ORGANIZATION plunged/O as/O much/O as/O 11/PERCENT percent/PERCENT ,/O while/O Finish/ORGANIZATION Line/ORGANIZATION Inc./ORGANIZATION fell/O 5.9/PERCENT percent/PERCENT ./O 
Dick/PERSON 's/O Sporting/ORGANIZATION Goods/ORGANIZATION Inc./ORGANIZATION dropped/O more/O than/O 9/PERCENT percent/PERCENT ./O 
European/MISC sellers/O Sports/ORGANIZATION Direct/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION Plc/ORGANIZATION and/O JD/ORGANIZATION Sports/ORGANIZATION Fashion/ORGANIZATION Plc/ORGANIZATION declined/O as/O well/O ./O 
Nike/ORGANIZATION gained/O as/O much/O as/O 1.8/PERCENT percent/PERCENT to/O $/MONEY 52.49/MONEY on/O Wednesday/DATE ,/O bringing/O its/O year-to-date/O gain/O to/O more/O than/O 3/PERCENT percent/PERCENT ./O 
Amazon/ORGANIZATION gained/O as/O much/O as/O 0.6/PERCENT percent/PERCENT to/O $/MONEY 998.70/MONEY ./O 
The/O Amazon/LOCATION partnership/O is/O part/O of/O Nike/ORGANIZATION 's/O push/O to/O boost/O sales/O directly/O to/O consumers/O to/O revive/O slowing/O growth/O that/O has/O weighed/O on/O its/O stock/O ./O 
Just/O last/DATE week/DATE ,/O Nike/ORGANIZATION announced/O a/O structural/O overhaul/O ,/O including/O cutting/O 1,400/O jobs/O ,/O to/O increase/O focus/O on/O direct/O ./O 
The/O company/O 's/O wholesale/O business/O --/O selling/O to/O retailers/O like/O Foot/O Locker/O --/O still/O makes/O up/O about/O 75/PERCENT percent/PERCENT of/O Nike/ORGANIZATION 's/O revenue/O ,/O but/O has/O been/O hurt/O by/O the/O woes/O of/O retailers/O ./O 
Last/DATE quarter/DATE ,/O direct-to-consumer/O revenue/O rose/O 18/PERCENT percent/PERCENT ,/O more/O than/O three/O times/O the/O growth/O rate/O of/O top-line/O revenue/O ./O 
The/O deal/O would/O help/O Nike/ORGANIZATION clean/O up/O the/O inventory/O that/O shows/O up/O on/O Amazon/LOCATION through/O third-party/O sellers/O ,/O Goldman/ORGANIZATION 's/O Drucker/PERSON Mann/PERSON said/O ./O 
It/O would/O also/O allow/O Nike/ORGANIZATION to/O compete/O better/O with/O Under/O Armour/O ,/O which/O already/O sells/O via/O Amazon/LOCATION ,/O and/O give/O it/O exposure/O to/O Millenial/O shoppers/O ,/O she/O said/O ./O 
She/O estimated/O Nike/ORGANIZATION 's/O move/O could/O eventually/O boost/O revenue/O by/O 1/PERCENT percent/PERCENT and/O push/O more/O brands/O to/O carry/O out/O similar/O deals/O ./O 
When/O brands/O work/O directly/O with/O Seattle-based/MISC Amazon/ORGANIZATION ,/O they/O can/O point/O out/O violations/O and/O have/O the/O counterfeit/O goods/O removed/O ./O 
Amazon/ORGANIZATION eventually/O aims/O to/O use/O machine/O learning/O to/O detect/O knockoff/O products/O before/O they/O 're/O even/O posted/O to/O the/O site/O ,/O the/O person/O familiar/O with/O the/O matter/O said/O ./O 
Almost/O 2,000/O branded/O products/O are/O registered/O in/O the/O Amazon/LOCATION program/O so/O far/O ,/O including/O Victoria/PERSON 's/O Secret/O ,/O Toms/ORGANIZATION ,/O Patagonia/LOCATION ,/O Johnson/ORGANIZATION &/ORGANIZATION Johnson/ORGANIZATION ,/O Clorox/ORGANIZATION and/O Procter/ORGANIZATION &/ORGANIZATION Gamble/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O person/O said/O ./O 
Amazon/ORGANIZATION 's/O anti-counterfeiting/O efforts/O appear/O to/O be/O working/O ./O 
Sandal-maker/O Birkenstock/LOCATION USA/LOCATION ,/O which/O last/O year/O announced/O it/O would/O stop/O selling/O products/O on/O Amazon/LOCATION due/O to/O concerns/O about/O fakes/O ,/O said/O Wednesday/DATE that/O it/O had/O ``/O seen/O improvements/O on/O the/O Amazon/LOCATION marketplace/O addressing/O our/O core/O issues/O of/O unauthorized/O sellers/O and/O counterfeit/O goods/O ./O ''/O 
``/O As/O a/O result/O ,/O we/O have/O continued/O to/O allow/O select/O third/O party/O sellers/O to/O list/O Birkenstock/O products/O on/O Amazon.com/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O U.S/LOCATION ,/O ''/O the/O company/O said/O ./O 
