Republican/MISC senators/O plan/O to/O write/O a/O health-care/O bill/O that/O could/O be/O radically/O different/O from/O the/O one/O passed/O last/O week/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O including/O keeping/O some/O of/O the/O benefits/O and/O safeguards/O currently/O enshrined/O within/O Obamacare/O ./O 
The/O Senate/ORGANIZATION 's/O different/O approach/O means/O there/O 's/O no/O clear/O timetable/O for/O producing/O a/O bill/O ,/O and/O it/O likely/O ensures/O that/O President/O Donald/PERSON Trump/PERSON and/O House/ORGANIZATION Republicans/MISC will/O eventually/O have/O to/O face/O legislation/O that/O does/O n't/O fully/O repeal/O the/O Affordable/O Care/O Act/O despite/O their/O repeated/O campaign/O promises/O to/O do/O it/O ./O 
``/O The/O Senate/ORGANIZATION is/O starting/O from/O scratch/O ,/O ''/O Republican/MISC Senator/O Susan/PERSON Collins/PERSON of/O Maine/LOCATION said/O during/O an/O interview/O on/O ABC/ORGANIZATION 's/O ``/O This/O Week/O ''/O on/O Sunday/DATE ./O 
``/O We/O 're/O going/O to/O draft/O our/O own/O bill/O ,/O and/O I/O 'm/O convinced/O that/O we/O 're/O going/O to/O take/O the/O time/O to/O do/O it/O right/O ./O ''/O 
Trump/PERSON on/O Sunday/DATE jawboned/O his/O party/O 's/O lawmakers/O ,/O saying/O on/O Twitter/O that/O ``/O Republican/MISC Senators/O will/O not/O let/O the/O American/MISC people/O down/O !/O ''/O 
Collins/PERSON ,/O who/O ranks/O among/O the/O most/O moderate/O of/O Republican/MISC senators/O ,/O and/O Senator/O Bill/PERSON Cassidy/PERSON of/O Louisiana/LOCATION said/O one/O of/O their/O top/O goals/O is/O to/O ensure/O that/O people/O with/O pre-existing/O medical/O conditions/O continue/O to/O have/O the/O same/O or/O better/O coverage/O ./O 
The/O pair/O have/O introduced/O a/O bill/O ,/O the/O Patient/MISC Freedom/MISC Act/MISC ,/O that/O keeps/O some/O of/O the/O consumer/O protections/O within/O Obamacare/O for/O people/O with/O pre-existing/O conditions/O while/O seeking/O to/O solve/O some/O of/O the/O flaws/O within/O the/O health-care/O law/O ./O 
While/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION bill/O that/O passed/O by/O a/O razor-thin/O margin/O on/O May/DATE 4/DATE requires/O states/O to/O provide/O coverage/O to/O people/O with/O pre-existing/O conditions/O ,/O that/O coverage/O might/O not/O be/O affordable/O ,/O Collins/PERSON said/O ./O 
``/O So/O much/O discretion/O is/O given/O to/O the/O states/O without/O any/O guardrails/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
Patients/O Over/O Party/O Cassidy/PERSON said/O on/O Fox/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION Channel/ORGANIZATION 's/O ``/O Sunday/DATE Morning/O Futures/O ''/O that/O he/O hopes/O a/O bill/O could/O be/O sent/O to/O Trump/PERSON by/O the/O fall/DATE ./O 
``/O This/O is/O not/O a/O Democratic/MISC issue/O ;/O it/O 's/O not/O a/O Republican/MISC issue/O ,/O ''/O said/O Cassidy/PERSON ,/O a/O physician/O ./O 
``/O Hopefully/O ,/O patients/O will/O take/O the/O precedence/O over/O party/O ./O ''/O 
Senator/O Roy/PERSON Blunt/PERSON of/O Missouri/LOCATION ,/O who/O 's/O part/O of/O the/O Republican/MISC leadership/O team/O ,/O said/O on/O NBC/ORGANIZATION 's/O ``/O Meet/O the/O Press/O ''/O that/O the/O goal/O for/O the/O Senate/ORGANIZATION should/O be/O a/O bill/O that/O brings/O people/O into/O the/O health-care/O system/O who/O are/O n't/O now/O in/O it/O ,/O ``/O to/O give/O people/O more/O choices/O ,/O to/O create/O more/O competition/O ./O ''/O 
Top/O House/O Republicans/MISC said/O they/O look/O forward/O to/O seeing/O what/O changes/O the/O Senate/ORGANIZATION makes/O to/O improve/O the/O bill/O ./O 
House/ORGANIZATION Speaker/O Paul/PERSON Ryan/PERSON said/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION added/O money/O for/O tax/O credits/O to/O help/O people/O ages/O 50/O and/O older/O pay/O for/O coverage/O ,/O and/O that/O he/O expects/O the/O Senate/ORGANIZATION will/O add/O to/O those/O tax/O credits/O and/O ``/O complete/O the/O job/O ./O ''/O 
``/O This/O is/O one/O stage/O in/O a/O multistage/O legislative/O process/O ,/O ''/O Ryan/PERSON said/O on/O ABC/ORGANIZATION 's/O ``/O This/O Week/O ./O ''/O 
Planned/O Parenthood/PERSON Collins/PERSON ,/O however/O ,/O said/O one/O of/O the/O problems/O with/O the/O tax/O credit/O in/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION bill/O is/O that/O it/O 's/O not/O adjusted/O for/O variations/O in/O income/O and/O geographic/O regions/O across/O the/O U.S./LOCATION ./O 
That/O ``/O really/O hurts/O a/O state/O like/O Maine/LOCATION ,/O where/O we/O have/O an/O older/O population/O ''/O living/O in/O rural/O areas/O where/O health/O care/O is/O more/O expensive/O ,/O she/O said/O ./O 
Separately/O ,/O on/O CBS/ORGANIZATION 's/O ``/O Face/O the/O Nation/O ,/O ''/O Democratic/MISC Senator/O Joe/PERSON Manchin/PERSON of/O West/LOCATION Virginia/LOCATION said/O his/O mostly/O poor/O and/O rural/O state/O ``/O gets/O absolutely/O slammed/O ''/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION health/O bill/O ./O 
Asked/O why/O 13/O men/O and/O no/O women/O had/O been/O picked/O for/O a/O Senate/ORGANIZATION working/O group/O on/O health/O care/O ,/O Collins/PERSON said/O ``/O the/O leaders/O obviously/O chose/O the/O people/O they/O want/O ./O ''/O 
Collins/PERSON said/O she/O 'd/O like/O to/O see/O a/O bipartisan/O group/O in/O the/O Senate/ORGANIZATION working/O on/O a/O bill/O ,/O with/O Democrats/MISC acknowledging/O that/O Obamacare/PERSON has/O problems/O and/O Republicans/MISC making/O sure/O that/O coverage/O is/O not/O reduced/O ./O 
She/O also/O said/O it/O would/O be/O ``/O not/O fair/O ''/O and/O ``/O a/O mistake/O ''/O to/O defund/O the/O women/O 's/O health/O clinics/O Planned/O Parenthood/O ./O 
``/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O low-income/O women/O should/O be/O denied/O their/O choice/O of/O health/O care/O providers/O ,/O for/O family/O planning/O ,/O cancer/O screenings/O ,/O for/O well-women/O care/O ,/O ''/O Collins/PERSON said/O ./O 
Even/O so/O ,/O Manchin/PERSON said/O Senate/ORGANIZATION Republicans/MISC have/O n't/O yet/O asked/O Democrats/MISC to/O work/O on/O a/O bill/O ./O 
``/O No/O one/O 's/O asked/O any/O Democrat/MISC ,/O and/O I/O 'm/O the/O most/O centrist/O Democrat/MISC willing/O to/O work/O and/O fix/O things/O if/O people/O really/O want/O to/O do/O it/O ,/O ''/O said/O Manchin/PERSON ,/O who/O 's/O up/O for/O re-election/O in/O 2018/DATE in/O a/O state/O that/O Trump/PERSON carried/O in/O 2016/DATE ./O 
Manchin/PERSON and/O Democratic/MISC Senator/O Dianne/PERSON Feinstein/PERSON of/O California/LOCATION ,/O who/O spoke/O on/O ``/O Meet/O the/O Press/O ''/O on/O Sunday/DATE ,/O both/O acknowledged/O there/O are/O problems/O with/O Obamacare/PERSON that/O need/O to/O be/O fixed/O ./O 
``/O Get/O rid/O of/O the/O word/O `/O repeal/O '/O and/O start/O talking/O about/O repairing/O ,/O ''/O Manchin/PERSON said/O ./O 
Feinstein/PERSON also/O noted/O the/O lack/O of/O women/O in/O the/O Republican/MISC working/O group/O ./O 
``/O Women/O 's/O health/O is/O a/O big/O part/O of/O this/O and/O women/O are/O a/O majority/O of/O the/O population/O ,/O and/O their/O health/O interests/O deserve/O to/O be/O contemplated/O in/O any/O reform/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
