Global/O electronics/O makers/O are/O scrambling/O to/O stock/O up/O on/O memory/O chips/O to/O keep/O production/O lines/O running/O as/O Apple/ORGANIZATION Inc/ORGANIZATION 's/O -LRB-/O AAPL.O/O -RRB-/O new/O iPhone/O 8/O launch/O later/O this/O year/O threatens/O to/O worsen/O a/O global/O squeeze/O on/O supply/O ./O 
While/O heavyweights/O such/O as/O Apple/ORGANIZATION and/O Samsung/ORGANIZATION Electronics/ORGANIZATION Co/ORGANIZATION Ltd/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O 005930/O ./O 
KS/O -RRB-/O -/O which/O is/O also/O the/O world/O 's/O top/O memory/O chip/O maker/O -/O will/O not/O be/O seriously/O hit/O ,/O industry/O sources/O and/O analysts/O say/O some/O electronics/O makers/O are/O paying/O a/O premium/O to/O lock/O into/O longer-term/O contracts/O ./O 
Others/O are/O placing/O orders/O earlier/O than/O before/O to/O ensure/O their/O perilously/O low/O inventories/O do/O no/O dry/O up/O completely/O ./O 
``/O After/O the/O supply/O shortages/O emerged/O we/O brought/O forward/O our/O procurement/O decisions/O .../O to/O ensure/O a/O stable/O supply/O ,/O ''/O smartphone/O and/O personal/O computer/O maker/O LG/ORGANIZATION Electronics/ORGANIZATION Inc/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O 066570/O ./O 
KS/O -RRB-/O said/O in/O a/O statement/O ,/O adding/O it/O had/O pushed/O up/O quarterly/O purchase/O decisions/O by/O about/O a/O month/O ./O 
Chip/O manufacturing/O technologies/O are/O growing/O increasingly/O complex/O ,/O raising/O investment/O costs/O yet/O providing/O less/O output/O growth/O as/O some/O suppliers/O struggle/O to/O improve/O yields/O ./O 
This/O has/O caused/O some/O chip/O prices/O to/O double/O or/O triple/O from/O a/O year/O earlier/O ./O 
Some/O analysts/O say/O device/O makers/O could/O be/O forced/O to/O cut/O down/O on/O the/O amount/O of/O DRAM/O chips/O ,/O which/O help/O devices/O perform/O multiple/O tasks/O at/O once/O ,/O or/O NAND/O chips/O that/O are/O used/O for/O long-term/O data/O storage/O ,/O on/O new/O products/O if/O the/O can/O not/O get/O enough/O chips/O ./O 
A/O chip/O supplier/O source/O told/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION a/O handful/O of/O clients/O have/O moved/O to/O 6-month/O supply/O agreements/O ,/O accepting/O higher/O prices/O than/O the/O customary/O quarterly/O or/O monthly/O deals/O ,/O to/O make/O sure/O they/O get/O enough/O memory/O chips/O for/O their/O products/O ./O 
``/O The/O problem/O will/O be/O more/O acute/O for/O the/O NAND/O market/O ,/O where/O the/O iPhone/O remains/O a/O critical/O source/O of/O demand/O given/O the/O huge/O sales/O volumes/O and/O recent/O moves/O to/O increase/O storage/O capacity/O on/O the/O device/O ,/O ''/O said/O the/O source/O ,/O who/O declined/O to/O be/O identified/O as/O he/O was/O not/O authorized/O to/O speak/O publicly/O on/O the/O matter/O ./O 
INVENTORY/O SQUEEZE/O Signs/O of/O stress/O have/O already/O emerged/O :/O Huawei/ORGANIZATION Technologies/ORGANIZATION Ltd/ORGANIZATION -LSB-/O HWT.UL/O -RSB-/O was/O criticized/O by/O consumers/O after/O it/O was/O discovered/O the/O Chinese/MISC firm/O used/O a/O mix/O of/O less/O advanced/O and/O powerful/O chips/O in/O its/O flagship/O P10/O model/O that/O led/O to/O significant/O variations/O in/O performance/O ./O 
Huawei/ORGANIZATION did/O not/O respond/O to/O requests/O for/O comment/O on/O its/O memory/O procurement/O plans/O ./O 
About/O 18/PERCENT percent/PERCENT of/O the/O global/O annual/O supply/O of/O NAND/O chips/O is/O bought/O by/O Apple/ORGANIZATION ,/O analysts/O say/O ./O 
In/O recent/O years/O ,/O electronics/O makers/O have/O typically/O built/O up/O inventory/O during/O the/O first/O half/O to/O avoid/O being/O squeezed/O by/O Apple/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O generally/O unveils/O its/O latest/O iPhone/O model/O in/O September/DATE ./O 
But/O the/O shortage/O of/O chips/O in/O the/DATE first/DATE half/DATE of/DATE the/DATE year/DATE has/O left/O many/O scrambling/O ./O 
Should/O the/O U.S./LOCATION giant/O opt/O to/O push/O out/O more/O iPhones/O than/O usual/O or/O further/O increase/O the/O portion/O of/O high-storage/O models/O ,/O that/O could/O further/O squeeze/O out/O other/O companies/O ./O 
Some/O analysts/O estimate/O Apple/ORGANIZATION could/O ship/O as/O many/O as/O 100/O million/O new/O iPhone/O 8s/O this/O year/O ,/O compared/O with/O the/O 82.3/O million/O iPhone/O 7s/O that/O Cowen/ORGANIZATION &/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION estimates/O for/O 2016/DATE ./O 
``/O For/O the/O iPhone/O 8/O launch/O there/O have/O been/O specific/O references/O to/O this/O by/O customers/O and/O distributors/O as/O a/O reason/O for/O longer/O delivery/O times/O and/O shortages/O ,/O ''/O said/O Tobey/PERSON Gonnerman/PERSON ,/O executive/O vice/O president/O at/O U.S.-based/MISC component/O distributor/O Fusion/O Worldwide/O ./O 
``/O Buying/O buffer/O stock/O and/O holding/O product/O in/O hubs/O to/O protect/O against/O anticipated/O delivery/O interruptions/O has/O certainly/O become/O more/O common/O in/O recent/O months/O ./O ''/O 
Apple/ORGANIZATION declined/O to/O comment/O on/O its/O memory/O chip/O purchasing/O plans/O ./O 
But/O analysts/O say/O meaningful/O new/O supply/O is/O unlikely/O to/O materialize/O until/O 2018/DATE ./O 
SK/ORGANIZATION Hynix/ORGANIZATION told/O Reuters/ORGANIZATION in/O a/O statement/O it/O has/O been/O meeting/O delivery/O dates/O but/O acknowledged/O supply/O conditions/O were/O tight/O ,/O noting/O its/O inventory/O levels/O were/O at/O an/O all-time/O low/O and/O unlikely/O to/O increase/O in/O the/O near-term/O given/O continued/O demand/O ./O 
Samsung/ORGANIZATION declined/O to/O comment/O on/O chip/O procurement/O for/O its/O electronic/O devices/O or/O inventory/O levels/O for/O its/O memory/O business/O ./O 
Smartphone/O makers/O in/O China/LOCATION are/O also/O locked/O in/O an/O arms/O race/O to/O provide/O the/O most/O memory/O ,/O which/O could/O further/O exacerbate/O the/O squeeze/O as/O they/O seek/O to/O counter/O the/O iPhone/O ./O 
Some/O investors/O and/O analysts/O have/O voiced/O concerns/O about/O potential/O ``/O de-speccing/O ,/O ''/O where/O product/O makers/O cut/O back/O on/O memory/O to/O cope/O with/O the/O shortages/O or/O margin/O pressures/O ./O 
IHS/ORGANIZATION analyst/O Walter/PERSON Coon/PERSON said/O some/O firms/O were/O starting/O to/O prepare/O to/O offer/O products/O with/O lower/O memory/O content/O if/O market/O conditions/O remain/O tight/O ./O 
But/O analysts/O also/O say/O manufacturers/O will/O be/O loath/O to/O cut/O back/O on/O memory/O as/O such/O a/O move/O would/O be/O deeply/O unpopular/O ,/O saying/O the/O firms/O are/O more/O likely/O to/O just/O not/O upgrade/O memory/O on/O new/O models/O ./O 
-LRB-/O $/MONEY 1/MONEY =/O 1,122.6500/O won/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O Reporting/O by/O Se/PERSON Young/PERSON Lee/PERSON ;/O additional/O reporting/O by/O Sijia/PERSON Jiang/PERSON in/O Hong/LOCATION Kong/LOCATION ,/O Jessica/PERSON Macy/PERSON Yu/PERSON in/O Taipei/LOCATION and/O Stephen/PERSON Nellis/PERSON in/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ;/O Editing/O by/O Alex/PERSON Richardson/PERSON -RRB-/O 
